<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-27T21:23:31-05:00</updated><id>https://hegels-code.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">hegel’s code</title><subtitle>Posts on Hegel&apos;s Phenomenology of Mind and Science of Logic</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The unfilling of the ‘I’ of its determinations</title><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/2025/02/26/PoM_The_unfilling_of_the_-I-_of_its_determinations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The unfilling of the ‘I’ of its determinations" /><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://hegels-code.github.io/2025/02/26/PoM_The_unfilling_of_the_%22I%22_of_its_determinations</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hegels-code.github.io/2025/02/26/PoM_The_unfilling_of_the_-I-_of_its_determinations.html"><![CDATA[<p>The phenomenology of the object on page 169-170 of the Harper Torchbook edition.</p>

<h4 id="perception">Perception:</h4>

<ol>
  <li>Sensation and its negation.  There is a general negation of negation, the medium.  It’s not quite an “I”.</li>
  <li>The negation of negation and its sensation, Being.  Sensation is now the negation of negation.  Pleasure is the opposite of pain.  Being is the opposite of Nothing.  But it’s searching for a “one”, a being that is not a negation of negation, its new lack.</li>
  <li>The interpretation is that I am an obstacle to Being, a body of organs.  I’m the medium of sensation and its negation.</li>
  <li>Actually. the medium is outside and my determinations are being-for-other.</li>
  <li>Our human determinations, the Understanding, are an obstacle to Being.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong><em>But the thing is a “one”; and we are aware in ourselves that this diversity, by which the thing ceases to be a unity, falls in us.  This thing, then, is, in point of fact, merely white to OUR eyes, also tart to OUR tongue, and also cubical to OUR feeling, and so on.  The entire diversity of these aspects comes not from the thing, but from us; and we find them falling apart thus from one another, because the organs they affect are quite distinct inter se, the eye is entirely distinct from the tongue, and so on.  We are consequently, the universal medium where such elements get dissociated, and exist each by itself.  By the fact, then that we regard the characteristic of being a universal medium as OUR reflection, WE preserve and maintain the self-sameness and truth of the thing, its being a “one”.</em></strong></p>

<p>What is the medium? Indeterminacy, over-determination, the absence of a principle of exclusion.  <br />
What is the difference between the first medium and the second medium?  The first medium is a lack of a principle of exclusion, while the second medium is a lack of exclusion within our reflection.<br />
Why does Hegel refer to <strong><em>our</em></strong> organs?  We cannot dissect ourselves.  Our bodies are known to us by the body of others.<br />
The body and its parts are a precursor of the thing and its properties.  The body is also the sense in which we have an “I” in this stage of development.  The “I” is filled with the determinations of the body and the medium doesn’t include a principle of exclusion.<br />
But there is a principle of exclusion from which the second medium is carved out, the one universal that rules them all, Being and its negation, our preservation, our self-sameness.</p>

<p>The principle of exclusion is the negative form (negation of negation) of self-sameness, just as pleasure is the opposite of pain.  This is why the development progresses from the abundance of sensation to Understanding or Intelligence.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The phenomenology of the object on page 169-170 of the Harper Torchbook edition.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mapping the Structure to the text of the Phenomenology_Continued</title><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/2025/01/19/PoM_Mapping_the-Structure_to-_the_text_-of_the_-Phenomenology_Continued.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mapping the Structure to the text of the Phenomenology_Continued" /><published>2025-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://hegels-code.github.io/2025/01/19/PoM_Mapping_the%20Structure_to%20_the_text_%20of_the_%20Phenomenology_Continued</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hegels-code.github.io/2025/01/19/PoM_Mapping_the-Structure_to-_the_text_-of_the_-Phenomenology_Continued.html"><![CDATA[<p>The phenomenology of the object on page 168-169 of the Harper Torchbook edition.</p>

<h4 id="perception">Perception:</h4>

<p><strong><em>Consciousness, then, has to go over this cycle again, but not in the same way as on the first occasion.</em></strong></p>

<p>Let’s revisit the repeating circuit of perception:</p>

<ol>
  <li>The object presents itself as a “one”.  I don’t see a “one” but it presents itself as a “one”.</li>
  <li>I see the property in it.  A property is the way we apprehend the object.</li>
  <li>I’m aware that I’m not seeing the object as I first thought, as a “one”, and the untruth belongs to me because the object is the essential fact.</li>
  <li>The “one” is now an extension of its properties, on account of the universality of properties themselves. 
But the continuity is actually a community of opposing and excluding properties.
It’s not the case that the salt is “white” and “tart” and “cubical”.  The object is “salt”.</li>
  <li>The “one” is only what I “mean”.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong><em>For it has found out, regarding perception, that the truth and outcome of perception is its dissolution, is reflection out of and away from the truth into itself.
In this way consciousness becomes definitely aware of how its perceptual process is essentially constituted, viz. that this is not a simple bare apprehension, but in its apprehension is at the same time reflected out of the true content and back into itself.</em></strong></p>

<p>Consciousness is aware that it is consciousness of consciousness of something, a Self.</p>

<p><strong><em>This return of consciousness into itself, which is immediately involved and implicated in that pure apprehension–for this return to self has proved to be essential to perception–alters the true content.</em></strong></p>

<p>We know how it alters the object, by its “sense existence”.</p>

<p><strong><em>Consciousness is aware that this aspect is at the same time its own, and takes it upon itself; and by so doing consciousness will thus get the true object bare and naked.</em></strong></p>

<p>Consciousness is both this aspect and aware of this aspect and if it takes ownership of it and removes it, it can get to the “bare and naked” object.</p>

<p><strong><em>In this way we have, now, in the case of perception, as happened in the case of sensuous certainty, the aspect of consciousness being forced back upon itself; but, in the first instance, not in the sense in which this took place in the former case–i.e not as if the truth of perception fell within it.  Rather consciousness is aware that the untruth, that comes out there, is within it.  By knowing this, however, consciousness is able to cancel and supersede this untruth.</em></strong></p>

<p>Sense-Certainty:</p>

<ol>
  <li>“This”.</li>
  <li>Not “This”.  The universal “This”.</li>
  <li>This “I”.</li>
  <li>Not this “I”, The universal “I”.</li>
  <li>Grasping, not pointing.</li>
</ol>

<p>In Sense-Certainty, ‘This “I”’ was the truth of the object but for the Self of Perception, it is the untruth of the object.</p>

<p><strong><em>It distinguishes its apprehension of the truth from the untruth of its perception, corrects this untruth, and, so far as itself takes in hand to make this correction, the truth, qua truth of perception, certainly falls within its own consciousness.  The procedure of consciousness, which we have now to consider, is thus so constituted that it no longer merely perceives, but is also conscious of its reflection into self, and keeps this apart from simple apprehension proper.</em></strong></p>

<p>Consciousness can grasp the truth of the object if it corrects its own untruth.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The phenomenology of the object on page 168-169 of the Harper Torchbook edition.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mapping the Structure to the text of the Phenomenology</title><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/12/15/PoM_Mapping_the-Structure_to-_the_text_-of_the_-Phenomenology.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mapping the Structure to the text of the Phenomenology" /><published>2024-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/12/15/PoM_Mapping_the%20Structure_to%20_the_text_%20of_the_%20Phenomenology</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/12/15/PoM_Mapping_the-Structure_to-_the_text_-of_the_-Phenomenology.html"><![CDATA[<p>A summary of the structure followed by its application to the phenomenology of the object on page 167-168 of the Harper Torchbook edition.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Opposition is the concept of the intellect.  This is the starting point, not sensation, such as the light we all see reflecting off of whatever.
Our identity is not in sense-certainity.</li>
  <li>From the multitude of oppositions, the one true opposition is being and nothing.  Our self-sameness is being, or nothing for that matter.</li>
  <li>Our senses are an obstacle to our self-sameness.</li>
  <li>Things are an obstacle to our self-sameness.</li>
  <li>Self-sameness is Understanding in Perception and Self-Consciousness in Understanding, an unfilling of sense-elements and thoughts respectively for the true self-sameness.</li>
</ol>

<h4 id="perception">Perception:</h4>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>“The object which I apprehend presents itself as purely “one” and single”</p>

    <p>Light, for instance, presents itself in its immediacy.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>“I am aware of the “property” in it, a property which is universal, thereby transcending the particularity of the object”</p>

    <p>The light is white. Properties are the implicit corollary of self-sameness and now light is mediated by its properties.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>“The first form of being, in which the objective reality has the sense of a “one”, was thus not its true being; and since the object is the true fact here,
the untruth falls on my side, and the apprehension was not correct”.</p>

    <p>The object is a fact whether perceived or not, whether the perceiver exists or not.  Consciousness perceives with a sense of not perceiving, so the untruth falls on us.  We are lacking.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>“On account of the universality of the property I must rather take the objective entity as a community in general.  I further perceive now the property to be determinate, opposed to another and excluding this other.  Thus, in point of fact, I did not apprehend the object rightly when I defined it as a “commonness” or community with others, or as a continuity; and must rather, taking account of the determinateness of the property, isolate parts within the community  and set down the object as a “one” that excludes.”</p>

    <p>At first, the properties form a community of universals we all share in common (a self-sameness).  This is our new self-sameness.  But in actuality, determinations are opposing and excluding so the community is really a community in conflict.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>In the disintegrated “one” I find many such properties, which do not affect one another, but are indifferent to one another.</p>

    <p>Maximum opposition and exclusion is the unfilling of the sense-elements from consciousness and the emergence of a new self-sameness, Understanding, if we are not to descend back to the beginning.  Our being is intelligence.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A summary of the structure followed by its application to the phenomenology of the object on page 167-168 of the Harper Torchbook edition.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Structure and Development of The Phenomenology of Mind: Perception_Revised_Version_2.0</title><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/11/11/PoM_Perception_Revised_Version_2.0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Structure and Development of The Phenomenology of Mind: Perception_Revised_Version_2.0" /><published>2024-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/11/11/PoM_Perception_Revised_Version_2.0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/11/11/PoM_Perception_Revised_Version_2.0.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-phenomenology-of-mind">The Phenomenology of Mind</h2>

<h4 id="perception">Perception:</h4>

<p>The following is described from the side of the subject but Perception is from the side of the object.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>No particular “here” and “now”.  The universal “here” and “now”; inside the medium.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The first determination is being.  Being is implicitly a negation and explicitly the “one”.</p>

    <p>Consciousness maintains (thinks) the “one” for its own preservation (sameness). 
 “thinking”, “being”, “oneness”, “sameness” all mean the same thing, but on the side of the object, in Perception, it is the “one”.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The apprehension of the “one” and the determinations of the sense-elements belonging to our organs and deceiving us.</p>

    <p>This is the self as a community of OUR organs and a stumbling block to apprehending the “one”.<br />
 This is the first explicit sense of self which will provide a new form of the object.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The apprehension of the “one” and the properties belonging to things.</p>

    <p>A thing is what opposes consciousness.  We apprehend the properties in things in the course of our experience in opposition to things.
 The salt is no longer white to my eyes, it is white in opposition to another thing that is black.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The apprehension of the “one” and the determinations of the intellect.</p>

    <p>The intellect is now an object of our apprehension of the “one”.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Phenomenology of Mind]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Structure and Development of The Phenomenology of Mind: Perception_Revised</title><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/10/26/PoM_Perception_Revised.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Structure and Development of The Phenomenology of Mind: Perception_Revised" /><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/10/26/PoM_Perception_Revised</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/10/26/PoM_Perception_Revised.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-phenomenology-of-mind">The Phenomenology of Mind</h2>

<h4 id="perception">Perception:</h4>

<p>The following is described from the side of the subject but Perception is from the side of the object.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>The plane of the universal</p>

    <p>The universal is not anything in particular.  It is a medium of negation of nothing in particular.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The plane of existence and the “one”.</p>

    <p>The “one” is specifically <strong>BEING</strong>.  You can negate all determinations except one, <strong>BEING</strong>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The plane of the self and the “one”.</p>

    <p>The self is deceived by its sense-elements from apprehending the “one”.  This is the stage of the empiricist.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The plane of the self as a being for other.  The self is a being for itself as it is for another.</p>

    <p>You are an other to yourself.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The plane of a specific intellect, Understanding.</p>

    <p>The intellect pervades all stages insofar as sense-certainty is actually a universal, but in the final 
 stage, consciousness has developed the intellect as an intellect, specifically the Understanding.</p>

    <p>The objects of consciousness are now thoughts.  This is the stage of the idealist.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Phenomenology of Mind]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The circuit of the Property in Perception</title><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/10/13/The-circuit-of-the-Property-in-Perception.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The circuit of the Property in Perception" /><published>2024-10-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/10/13/The%20circuit%20of%20the%20Property%20in%20Perception</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/10/13/The-circuit-of-the-Property-in-Perception.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hegel has established the universal medium of the “this” and “now”.  There is no way out of it.  The intellect operates inside the medium of the universals of space and time.  Sense-certainity is an abstraction, meaning it is the negation of the intellect without actually negating the intellect.</p>

<p>If we proceed from the most familiar to us to the least familiar, we  move to the more conceptual and real where the two can lose distinction.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Properties as aspects of consciousness, which are opposing and excluding determinations.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Before that, there are proper properties, they belong to the thing.  A property doesn’t exist before it belongs to something.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Before proper properties there are several properties in the thing.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Finally, before several properties in the thing there are many ones.  The requirement of self-relation, oneness.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Before the ones, there is the universal medium.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>The reverse is equally true.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>The universal medium.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The “one”.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The properties of the “one”.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The essential property of the “one”.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The properties of consciousness.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hegel has established the universal medium of the “this” and “now”. There is no way out of it. The intellect operates inside the medium of the universals of space and time. Sense-certainity is an abstraction, meaning it is the negation of the intellect without actually negating the intellect.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mapping Perception in Phenomenology and Existence in Logic</title><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/09/07/Mapping-Perception-and-Existence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mapping Perception in Phenomenology and Existence in Logic" /><published>2024-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/09/07/Mapping%20Perception%20and%20Existence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/09/07/Mapping-Perception-and-Existence.html"><![CDATA[<p>Do we rejoice in eternal recurrence and engage in endless determination or should the matter be settled?</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Perception</th>
      <th>Existence</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>1. Medium of Universals.</td>
      <td>1. The back and forth of Being and Nothing. If neither Being nor Nothing alter, you are stuck in an endless circuit.  Also, you neither terminate with Being nor Nothing, you only determine.  In other words, there is really only coming-into-being and going-out-of-being, Becoming, what’s in-between.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>2. The moment of negation, negation of not-being.  Example: You are walking along a path. An obstacle stops you. You walk around the obstacle or move the obstacle out of the way. This is not a “one”. You walk around the obstacle, the obstacle moves back in front of you or it resists being moved. This is a “one”.</td>
      <td>2.   The first negation of negation, something.  Existence determines the something.  Example: I fail to negate the something and the something attempts to negate me.  It’s only when I capitulate to the something for my own preservation is something truly something.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>3. Self and Self-deception.  When I fail to know the “one” as “one”; I am deceived when my preservation is at stake.</td>
      <td>3. The something as the other of the other.  The something as being-for-other.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>4. Opposition and being-for-self and being-for-another.</td>
      <td>4. Over the course of experience, the something as being-for-other vacillates between Constitution (being-for-other) and Determination (being-in-itself). And just as Existence was posited from the back and forth of Being and Nothing, existence in general is posited from being-for-other and being-in-itself because this too if it doesn’t posit something will get stuck in an endless circuit.  There are two somethings, an existence in general and the unsettled bifurcated something as Constitution and Determination.  Existence in general posits a new form of determinateness, limit.  The something, for instance, is quantifiable.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>5. The new knowledge of Understanding.</td>
      <td>5. The something existed as the content of my preservation.  Infinite being now exists as the form of my preservation.</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Being is the historical determinations up to the point when Hegel realized it doesn’t need to go further to be understood.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do we rejoice in eternal recurrence and engage in endless determination or should the matter be settled?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Structure and Development of The Phenomenology of Mind: Understanding</title><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/04/27/PoM_Understanding.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Structure and Development of The Phenomenology of Mind: Understanding" /><published>2024-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/04/27/PoM_Understanding</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/04/27/PoM_Understanding.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-phenomenology-of-mind">The Phenomenology of Mind</h2>

<h4 id="understanding-the-logic-of-syllogism">Understanding (the logic of syllogism):</h4>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>The objects for understanding are thoughts, but they are still objects.  Things are not simply cubicle and white, but malleable and porous, because thoughts are malleable and porous.  Thoughts can also be negated and superseded.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Thought recoils from  both its negation and expression.  This is Force.</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code> The development of Force in consciousness:
	  
 1. Force is a Force expressed.  It has already expressed itself.  
 2. Force expressed incites Force repressed. 
 Force repressed is neither a cancelled Force nor an expression of Force.   
 3. Force repressed incites expressed (Force repressed).  
 4. Expressed (Force repressed) incites repressed (expressed (Force repressed)).  
 5. The negation of the moments is the notion of Force.
	
 Example of Force:
 1. Desire is Desire fulfilled.
 2. Repressed Desire.
 3. Desire for the Repressed Desire.  Desire for the Desire.
 4. New repressed Desire.  The Desire of the other and my Desire as the other Desire. 
 5. The negation of the moments.  The mutual recognition of Desire for Desire.
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The two vanishing moments (expressed and repressed force) is for us the notion as notion but for consciousness it is the inner nature of things because it is still for it an objective process.</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code> The development of Force as the inner nature of things (supersensible world):
	  
 1. Flux or Appearance. The object of understanding from the implicit attitude of notion as notion. (Force expressed)
 2. Universal difference, negation of difference, Law of difference.  These all mean the same. (Force repressed)
 3. The diversity of laws because Appearance has independence from the inner world.  
 The diversity of laws is Appearance mediated by the Law. Expressed (Force repressed) 
 Laws are too abstract to encompass Appearance but the plurality of law is equally a defect
 to the inner unity of the understanding as notion as notion.
 4. Law of Law. The inner of the inner. Universal Attraction is the conception of law.  
 Everything has a constant distinction to everything. Universal Attraction is the mediated form of Law. 
 Repressed (expressed (Force repressed))  
 5. The inner necessity of Law is the necessity of the inner unity of Law.
 This was already found to be true in the play of forces.  There is one force. 
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>There are two aspects to the law, its inner necessity on the side of the concept and the being of law on the side of the object.</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code> The development of the concept of force in the understanding:
	  
 1. A law is expressed.
 2. It is apprehended as a force, a universal.
 3. The force (concept) has laws (being).
 4. The indifference of force to its laws.  There are several forms that the indifference takes:
 a. The distinctions of the law are properties of force, but as properties, they are not necessary to it.
 Opposition between whole and parts.
 b. The distinctions of the law is its notion, which means its existence is not necessary or it exists 
 through other forces, which is a plurality of laws. No opposition between whole and parts.  
 c. The distinctions of the law are indifferent to each other, as in the notion of motion where distance
 and velocity can be independent of each other.  Opposition between all the parts, including the whole.
 These attitudes fail to find the necessity of the law.  
 5. The distinction of the law is the notion of distinction and the distinction of the notion.
 They are both the same.  Understanding, however, is only reflecting its own necessity. 
 The process in which a distinction is made and subsequently cancelled and transcended is called Explanation.
			
 If force (concept) and the law (being) are not distinct, the law is not an explanation of anything.
 Explanation is a tautological process that explains nothing. Tautological means self-identical,
 and the self-identity of the elements is absolute change.
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The new law and the true inner necessity of the law.</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code> 1. Previously Law proceeded from change.  Now change proceeds from Law.  This is absolute change.
 2. The second law is no longer the law of identity.  It is the law of unlike becoming like and like becoming unlike.
 3. The second supersensible world.  The inverted world.  The expressed (Force repressed) world.
 4. Infinity. There is an inner distinction and not a distinction between separate elements.  The inverted world
 is an inversion of itself, an expression of repression and a repression of expression.
 This realizes the conception of the inner necessity of Law.
 5. Infinity is the same process as Force and Law but as an object of understanding.
 This is Self-consciousness.  Infinity means the process can no longer be logically negated and superseded.
 The process has ended and can now be elaborated.
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Phenomenology of Mind]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Structure and Development of The Phenomenology of Mind: Sense-Certainty and Perception</title><link href="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/04/18/PoM_Sense-Certainty_Perception.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Structure and Development of The Phenomenology of Mind: Sense-Certainty and Perception" /><published>2024-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/04/18/PoM_Sense-Certainty_Perception</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hegels-code.github.io/2024/04/18/PoM_Sense-Certainty_Perception.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-phenomenology-of-mind">The Phenomenology of Mind</h2>

<h4 id="sense-certainty-the-logic-of-identity">Sense-Certainty (the logic of identity):</h4>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>This.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Not This.  The universal.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Not (Not This). The immediate fact of the “I”.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Not (Not (Not This)).  The “I” is a universal and consciousness is not the “I” looking, it is–looking.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The negation of the moments is Perception.</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code> Consciousness takes the path of thinking (grasping) and recoils from the paths of annihilation.     
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ol>

<h4 id="perception-the-logic-of-contradiction">Perception (the logic of contradiction):</h4>

<p>The following is described from the side of the subject but Perception is from the side of the object.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>The medium. This, and also this, and also this, and also this, and also this, and so on.</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code> All universals are reflected into self, passive, equal, and indeterminate.
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The moment of negation. Not this, you can exclude it, not this, you can exclude it, not this, you can exclude it, and so on.  Not <strong>Being</strong>, you can not exclude it, it is the one universal you can not exclude.</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code> Being is the "one" (universal) you cannot exclude.  
 The rest are properties of the "one", the world that makes me be.
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The medium is our reflection.  The properties of the (reflected into) self.</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code> The world that makes me laugh, the world that makes me cry, the world that makes me angry, and so on.
 But the "one" is the self-same; I laugh, cry, and get angry.  
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The properties of the self and the opposition to the many “ones” that have properties of their own.</p>

    <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code> A "one" opposes consciousness and cannot be excluded.
 That is what makes it a "one" and not a property of a "one" or a property of consciousness.
 Consciousness determines through its experience that its properties are properties for another.  It is an other. 
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The moment of negation.  The unconditioned universal is the (reflected into) self without properties.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Phenomenology of Mind]]></summary></entry></feed>